

MD SAYEED ABID

Contact:

+8801704605452

Email:

sayeedabids@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/in/sayeed-abid-efaz25

Digital Portfolio: sayeedabid.github.io

Address:

14, 14/1 Diluroad, New Eskaton, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Nationality: Bangladeshi

Summary

Passionate about the field of Artificial Intelligence (AI), Machine Learning and Deep Learning with research experience in relevant fields. Specialized in data visualization, data analysis, algorithm design and various deep learning applications. Along with this 1 year of extensive experience in software development industry. Seeking position in these fields to apply my experiences and skills to ace.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science & Engineering (BS CSE)

Institute: North South University, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Passing Year: 2021

Specialization: Artificial Intelligence

CGPA: 3.53/4.00 (with distinction 'Cum Laude')

Higher Secondary School Certificate (HSC)

Institute: Notre Dame College, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Passing Year: 2016 GPA: 5.00/5.00

Secondary School Certificate (SSC)

Institute: Willes Little Flower School & College, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Passing Year: 2014 GPA: 5.00/5.00

PROJECTS

- ❖ Generalization of Bangla Sign Language Recognition using Angular Loss Function (**Published** in IEEE Access Journal, volume 9,2021)
- ❖ Local Climate Zone Mapping using Clustering Algorithms: A case study of Dhaka, Bangladesh (**Accepted** in IGARSS 2022)
- ❖ RER: Recycled Experience Replay, Blending Oldest Memories with Recent Selective Experiences to Improve Remembering (Ongoing) (Funded by CTRG 2021-2022, North South University)
- ❖ Mathematical Analysis of Covid-19 Outbreak in Bangladesh
- ❖ Image Super-resolution to Improve Classification Quality using GANs
- **❖** Hazimart App by Grabsoft

SKILLS

General skills:

- o Public speaking and efficient in communication.
- o Good leadership quality and adaptable in every situation.
- o Ability to handle various kind of people.

Technical skills:

- o Coding skills: Python, Java, C programming, Html5, CSS
- o **Familiar with:** Assembly language, Flutter
- o AI Libraries: PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras, Numpy, Matplotlib, Pandas
- o Web Frameworks: Django, Bootstrap
- o Can work with: Windows, Linux, Android, IOS
- o **Database:** Firebase, MySQL
- o MS Office: MS Word, MS Powerpoint, MS Excel
- o **Editing skills**: Adobe Photoshop CC, Adobe Lightroom

IELTS Score

Overall: 7.5

Listening: 8.5 Speaking: 7.5 Reading: 7.0 Writing: 6.5

References

Dr. Shahnewaz Siddique Assistant Professor, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, North South University Dhaka, Bangladesh

Email:

shahnewaz.siddique@northsouth.edu

Dr. Nabeel Mohammed Associate Professor, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, North South University Dhaka, Bangladesh

Email:

nabeel.mohammed@northsouth.edu



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

North South University

- o Research Assistant: August, 2021 Present (Part-time)
- Responsibilities: Conducting various research experiments, Writing research articles, Assisting other students on their projects.

Grabsoft IT and Software Firm

- o Front-End Developer: April, 2020 August, 2021 (Part-time)
- Responsibilities: Front-End designing for android apps and websites,
 Requirement analysis, Application testing.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

NSU Public Health and Sciences Club

Working Period: 2019 – 2021

Positon: **Treasurer**

Experiences:

- o Organized the event on "World diabetics day 2019"
- Organized seminars on various national and international issues
- o Organized multiples webinars for post covid-19 situations

NSU Computer and Engineering Club (NSUCEC)

Working Period: 2017 – 2019

Position: Promotion & Publication In-Charge

Experiences:

- o Organizer at Robo Quest 2018
- o Organizer at Cybernauts 2018
- o Organizer at Bit Arena V2 2017

Notre Dame Nature Study Club (NDNSC)

Working Period: 2014 – 2016 Position: **Vice President**

Experiences:

- o Organizer at Green Inspiration 2nd International Nature Summit 2016
- Organizer at 6th National Nature Festival 2015
- o Organizer at 1st International Nature Summit 2015
- o Organizer at 5th National Nature Festival 2014
- o Achievement: LTMA (Life Time Membership Award)